Everybody. Shh. Uh, Central Perk is proud to present...
大家请安静一下 下面有请
...the music of Miss Phoebe Buffay.
菲比·布菲 为大家表演
Thanks.
谢谢
Hi. Um, I wanna start with a song that's about that moment...
我接下来唱的歌 表达了当你突然...
...when you suddenly realize what life is really all about.
看清生活本来面目时的感受
Okay, here we go.
好了 开始吧
Okay. Thank you very much.
好吧 谢谢大家
What...?
咋了
Oh, great. This is just...
我晕 真是太...
老·友·记
S01E07  The One with the Blackout
第一季第七集  纽约大停电
■
字幕制作
Subtitled By
@张纳德nerd
■
讨论邮箱
Discuss
f6dicuss@163.com (或私信)
■
鸣谢
Special Thanks
Psychd(英文字幕)
This is so cool, you guys.
还挺好看的啊
The entire city's blacked out.
整个城市都停电了
Mom says it's Manhattan, Brooklyn and Queens...
我妈说曼哈顿 布鲁克林和皇后区都停电了
...and doesn't know when it'll be back on.
而且不知道什么时候恢复
You guys, this is big.
那这事可严重了
Pants and a sweater. Why, Mom?
裤子和毛衣 怎么了
Who will I meet in a blackout?
停电了我和谁约会啊
Power-company guys? Eligible looters?
电力公司的 还是趁黑天打劫的啊
Can we talk about this later? Okay.
以后再聊行吗 拜拜
Can I borrow the phone?
能用一下电话吗
I wanna call my apartment and check on my grandma.
我想给我奶奶打个电话
What's my number?
我家电话是多少来着
I never call me.
我又没给自己打过
Oh, my God. It's her.
我靠 这不是她吗
It's that Victoria Secret model.
维密秀的模特
(美国一年一度的内衣秀)
Something Goodacre.
古雅克什么的
Hi, Mom, it's Jill.
嗨 妈 我是吉尔
She's right. It's Jill. Jill Goodacre.
没错 吉尔·古雅克
Oh, my God.
我了个去
I am trapped in an ATM vestibule with Jill Goodacre.
我和吉尔·古雅克一起困在ATM厅里了
Is it a vestibule? Maybe it's an atrium?
厅不确切 这算是屋吧
Yeah, that is the part to focus on, you idiot.
对 继续纠结这个吧 白痴
Yeah, I'm fine. I'm just stuck at the bank in an ATM vestibule.
没事 只是被关在银行ATM厅里了
Jill says vestibule...
吉尔说的是厅
...I'm going with vestibule.
那我也说厅好了
I'm fine.
我挺好的
No, I'm not alone.
不是 还有别人
I don't know. Some guy.
不认识 一个男生
Oh, some guy. I am some guy.
一个男生 我是个小男生
Hey, Jill, I saw you with some guy last night.
吉尔 昨天我看见你和一个男生在一起啊
Yes, he was some guy.
没错 一个男生
Officiating at tonight's blackout is Rabbi Tribbiani.
主持今晚停电聚会的是 拉比·崔比昂尼
(Rabbi是个犹太名字 罗斯在调侃乔伊拿的蜡烛)
Chandler's old roommate was Jewish, and these are the only candles we have...
钱德的前室友是个犹太人 我们只有这种蜡烛
...so happy Hanukkah.
光明节快乐吧
Ooh, look. Ugly Naked Guy lit a bunch of candles.
快看 丑裸男正点蜡烛呢
Ooh. That had to hurt.
一定疼死了
All right, all right. It's been 14 and a half minutes...
冷静 已经过了14分半钟了
...and you still haven't said one word. Oh, God.
你居然一个字都没说出来
Do something. Just make contact. Smile.
做点啥交流一下啊 微笑吧
There you go.
这就对了
You're definitely scaring her.
现在你吓到她了
Uh, would you like to call somebody?
你想打给谁吗
Yeah, about 300 guys I went to high school with.
有 想给高中的300多个校友打
Yeah, thanks.
好 谢谢
-It's me. -It's Chandler.
-是我  -钱德打来的
Are you okay?
你还好吗
Yeah, I'm fine.
还不错
I'm stuck in an ATM vestibule...
我和吉尔·古雅克
...with Jill Goodacre.
被困在ATM厅里了
What?
啥
I'm stuck...
我和
...in an ATM vestibule...
吉尔·古雅克
...with Jill Goodacre.
一起困在ATM厅里了
I have no idea what you said.
完全听不懂
Put Joey on the phone.
让乔伊接电话
What's up, man?
咋了 少年
I'm stuck...
我和
...in an ATM vestibule...
吉尔·古雅克
...with Jill Goodacre.
一起困在ATM厅里了
Oh, my God.
我的天啊
He's trapped in an ATM vestibule with Jill Goodacre.
他和吉尔·古雅克被困到ATM厅里了
Chandler, listen.
钱德 这样
Yeah, like that thought never entered my mind.
废话 我都想过无数次了
Come on, somebody.
来个人先说啊
I'll go. I'll go.
我先来
Okay, um, senior year of college, on a pool table.
大学二年级 在台球桌
Pool table?
台球桌
That's my sister.
我妹就是这么狂野
Okay, okay. My weirdest place would have to be...
到我了 我最奇怪的地点是...
...the women's room on the second floor of the New York City Public Library.
纽约市图书馆二层的女厕所
Oh, my God. What were you doing in a library?
我晕 你去图书馆干嘛啊
-Pheebs, what about you? -Oh, um, Milwaukee.
-菲比 你呢  -密尔沃基
Uh, Ross?
罗斯呢
Disneyland, 1989. "It's a small world after all."
1989年 迪士尼乐园的'奇幻王国'
No way.
不会吧
The, uh, ride broke down...
当时机械故障了
...so Carol and I went behind a couple of those mechanical Dutch children.
所以我和卡萝就到一群荷兰小人的后面...
They fixed the ride, and we were asked never to return to the Magic Kingdom.
之后故障修好了 我俩被惩罚再也不能去'奇幻王国'玩
Ooh. Rachel?
瑞秋呢
I already went.
我说过了啊
-You did not go. -Yes, I did.
-你没说过  -我说了
Tell us. Come on.
快说吧
All right, uh, the weirdest place would have to be...
好吧 我最奇怪的场所是...
...the foot of the bed.
床脚
-Step back. -We have a winner.
-大家退后一步  -赢家产生啦
I've never had a relationship with that kind of passion.
我从来没有过一段激情燃烧的感情
Where you have to have somebody right there in the middle of a theme park.
像你和卡萝在主题公园里做的那样
It was the only thing to do there that didn't have a line.
当时只有那里没人排队
Well, Barry wouldn't even kiss me on a miniature-golf course.
巴瑞就算在迷你高尔夫的课上都不肯亲我
-Come on. -No.
-不是吧  -真的
He said we were holding up the people behind us.
他会说我们耽误后面的人了
And you didn't marry him because?
你没嫁给他是因为啥来着
Do you think there are people that go through life...
你说有没有可能 两个人过了一辈子
...never having that kind of?
但从来没有过激情
-Probably. -Really?
-有可能  -真的啊
I'll tell you something. Passion is way overrated.
要我说吧 激情这点被大家夸大了
-Yeah, right. -It is.
-是 没错  -真的
Eventually, it kind of burns out.
最后 激情总会消退的
But hopefully what you're left with is trust and security and, uh...
但是不会消失的是信任和安全感 以及...
In my ex-wife's case, lesbianism.
从卡萝来看 同性恋情结
For all those people who miss out on that, uh, passion thing...
所以那些没有激情的伴侣之间
...there's other good stuff.
还是会有很多珍贵的东西
Okay.
也是
But, um, I don't think that'll be you.
但是我觉得你应该不会
You don't?
我不会吗
See, I see, uh...
我感觉 你的未来
...big passion in your future.
会充满激情
Really?
真的吗
-You do? -I do.
-真是这么想的  -必须的
Ross, you're so great.
罗斯 你太好了
It's never gonna happen.
你俩没戏
-What? -You and Rachel.
-啥  -你和瑞秋
Why not?
为啥啊
Because you waited too long to make your move...
因为你行动之前等太久了
...and now you're in the "Friend Zone."
现在你已经处于'朋友圈'里了
No, no, no. I'm not in the Zone.
没有 我才没在圈里呢
No, Ross. You're mayor of the Zone.
少来了 你简直是一圈之长啊
Look, I'm taking my time, all right?
我在等待时机好吗
I'm laying the groundwork.
我正在打基础
Every day I get a little bit closer to, uh...
我每天都在一点点靠近...
Priesthood.
神父
Ross, I'm telling you, she has no idea what you're thinking.
我很确定 她完全不知道你在想什么
If you don't ask her out soon, you'll end up stuck in the Zone forever.
如果你不马上采取行动 你就永远被困在圈子里了
I will, I will.
我会的
I'm waiting for the, uh, right moment.
我只是在等合适的时间
What?
咋了
-What, now? -Yeah.
-现在吗  -是啊
What's messing you up? The wine?
你还想怎样 有酒
The candles? The moonlight? Huh?
蜡烛 还有月光
You gotta go up to her and say, "Look, Rachel, I think..."
你需要做的就是走上前说 '瑞秋 我觉得...'
-What are we shushing? -We're shushing...
-嘘什么呢  -我们在...
...because we're trying to hear something.
试着听一个声音
-What? -Uh, don't you hear that?
-啥声音  -你没听见吗
See?
是吧
-Would you like some gum? -Oh. Is it sugarless?
-要口香糖不  -是无糖的吗
-Uh, sorry, it's not. -Then, no, thanks.
-不好意思 不是  -那不要了 谢谢
What the hell was that?
你妹的搞什么呢啊
Mental note: If Jill Goodacre offers you gum, you take it.
心灵备忘录 '如果吉尔给你口香糖 吃就得了'
If she offers you mangled animal carcass, you take it.
'就算给砍过的动物尸体 你也得拿着'
New York City has no power
纽约市停电了
And the milk is getting sour
我的牛奶要变酸了
But to me it is not scary
但是我并不在意
'Cause I stay away from dairy
因为我不喝牛奶
-Here goes. -You'll do it?
-我去了  -你要上了
-I'll do it. -Want help?
-是的  -需要我帮助吗
You come out there, you're a dead man.
你敢出来我就削死你
Ross, Ross.
罗斯 等等
Good luck, man.
祝你好运
Thanks.
谢谢
-Okay. -Okay.
-好了  -好了
-Where you going?  -Outside.
-去哪啊  -阳台
You can't go out there.
你不能去
-Why not? -Because of, uh, the reason.
-为啥  -因为...一个原因
And that would be?
什么原因啊
I, uh... I can't tell you.
我不能告诉你
What's going on?
到底怎么了
Okay, listen. You gotta promise you'll never, ever tell Ross that I told you.
好吧 但是你一定别告诉罗斯是我说的
-About what? -He's planning your birthday party.
-啥啊  -他在给你准备生日聚会
Oh, my God. I love him.
天啊 我爱死他了
You better act surprised.
最好表现的惊讶点
-About what? -My surprise party.
-说啥呢  -我的惊喜派对
-What surprise party? -Oh, stop it. Joey already told me.
-什么派对  -别装了 乔伊都告诉我了
Well, he didn't tell me.
他没告诉我啊
Don't look at me. This is Ross' thing.
别看我啊 罗斯出的主意
This is so typical. I'm always the last to know everything.
总是这样 所有事我都最后一个知道
You are not. We tell you stuff.
才不是呢 我们都和你说啊
I was the last one to know when Chandler got bit by the peacock at the zoo.
钱德在动物园被孔雀咬了 我最后知道的
I was the last to know you had a crush on Joey when he was moving in.
乔伊搬过来的时候你暗恋过他 我也是最后
What?
啥
Oh. Looks like I was second to last.
噢 看来我是倒数第二个啊
It's so nice.
太美了
Hey, I have a question.
我有个问题
Uh, actually, it's not so much a question...
其实也不算是个问题啦
...it's more of a general wondering...
顶多算是一个小怀...
...ment.
疑问
-Okay. -Okay.
-好的  -那我说了
Here goes.
是这样
Um, well, for a while now, I've been wanting to, um...
我很长时间以前就想要...
Yes, that's right.
没错就是这样
Look at that little kitty.
快看那只小猫
What?
什么
I'm on the top of the world Looking down on creation
我站在世界之巅俯视红尘
('Top of the world' By Karen Carpenter)
All right, this is just Bactine. It won't hurt.
这是云南白药 不疼
Sorry, that was wax.
抱歉 蜡烛滴下去了
Poor little Tootie's scared. We should find his owner.
这小家伙都惊呆了 我们得找到它的主人
Why not put "poor little Tootie" in the hall?
为啥不直接把它放到走廊里
During a blackout? She'll get trampled.
现在可停电呢 它会被人欺负的
Yeah?
确定吗
You know, on second thought, gum would be perfection.
我琢磨了一下 现在吃口香糖简直完美
Gum would be perfection?
吃口香糖完美
Gum would be perfection.
Could've said, "Gum would be nice."
本来可以说'吃口香糖挺不错的'
"I'll have a stick." But, no.
或者'我还是来一块吧'...但偏偏没有
For me, gum is perfection.
对我 口香糖就是完美的
I loathe myself.
我都鄙视我自己
Oh, no, the Mellons. They hate all living things, right?
梅伦家 他们讨厌所有生物吧
Hi. We just found this cat...
嗨 我们刚遇到了一只猫
...and we're looking for the owner.
我们正在找它的主人
Um, yeah, it's, uh... It's mine.
噢 没错 是我的猫
He seems to hate you. Are you sure?
它看起来不喜欢你啊
Yeah. It's my cat. Give me my cat.
没错 就是我的 快还给我
Wait a minute. What's his name?
等等 它叫什么
Um, Bob... Buttons.
额 纽扣鲍伯
Bob Buttons?
纽扣鲍勃
Bob Buttons. Here, Bob Buttons.
快来这 小纽扣
You are a very bad man.
你真是太恶劣了
You owe me a cat.
你们欠我一只猫
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty.
小猫你在哪呢
Where did you go, little kitty, kitty, kitty?
小猫你跑哪去了啊
Come on, lucky sixes.
快来六啊
Everybody, this is Paolo.
大家好 这是保罗
Paolo, I want you to meet my friends.
保罗 这是我的朋友们
This is Monica...
这是莫妮卡
...and Joey...
这是乔伊
...and Ross.
还有罗斯
Ha, ha. He doesn't speak much English.
他英语不太好
Monopoly.
大富翁
Look at that.
没错
So, uh...
这...
Where did, uh, Paolo come from?
保罗是哪的
Italy, I think. Heh.
意大利吧 我感觉
No, I mean tonight, in the building? Suddenly into our lives?
是在这栋楼里吗 突然就闯进我们的生活了
The cat turned out to be Paolo's cat. Isn't that funny?
那只猫的主人就是保罗 有意思吧
That is funny. And Rachel keeps touching him.
真有意思 而且瑞秋抱着他不撒手了
I looked all over the building and I couldn't find the kitty anywhere.
我找遍了 到处都找不到猫
Oh, I found him. It was Paolo's cat.
我找到了 猫是保罗的
Ah. Well, there you go. Last to know again.
看吧 又是最后一个知道的
And I'm guessing, since nobody told me, this is Paolo?
因为没人告诉我 那我猜这位就是保罗吧
Oh. Paolo, this is Phoebe.
噢 保罗 这是菲比
You betcha.
那必须的
All right. Okay. What next?
冷静 接下来咋办
Blow a bubble. A bubble's good.
吹个泡泡 应该不错吧
It's got a, uh, boyish charm. It's impish.
显得我很有童心
Here we go.
走你
Nice going, imp.
干得不错 傻小子
Okay. It's okay. All I need to do is...
没关系 现在只需要...
...reach over and put it back in my mouth.
捡回来放回嘴里
Good save. We're back on track and I'm...
救得好 现在重回正轨 而且...
...chewing someone else's gum.
嚼的是别人的口香糖
This is not my gum.
不是我的口味啊
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
我靠 恶心死了
And now you're choking.
现在还噎住了
Are you all right?
你还好吗
Oh, my God. You're choking.
天啊 你噎住了
Better?
好点了吗
Yes.
好多了
Thank you. That was...
谢谢 刚才真是...
That was...
刚才真是...
Perfection?
完美
What'd he say that was so funny?
他说啥呢 这么好笑
I have absolutely no idea.
完全没听懂
That's classic.
合情合理
My God, you guys. What am I doing?
我这是在干什么呢啊
This is so un-me.
真是太不像我了
If you want, I'll do it.
愿意的话 我可以替你上
I know. I just wanna bite his bottom lip.
我只想咬住他的下嘴唇
But I won't.
但我不会的
God. The first time he smiled at me...
他第一次对我微笑的时候
...those three seconds were more exciting than three weeks in Bermuda with Barry.
那三秒钟比和巴瑞在百慕大过三个星期还激情
Did you rent mopeds?
当时你们租摩托车了吗
Because I've heard...
因为我听说...
Oh, it's not about that right now. Okay.
现在不是说那个呢啊 好吧
I know it's totally superficial, and we have nothing in common...
我知道这很肤浅 而且我们没什么共同点
...and we don't even speak the same language...
我们甚至语言都不通
...but, God.
但是 我靠
Paolo, hi.
保罗 嗨
-Ross. -Listen, uh...
-罗斯  -听着
Listen, um, heh, something you should, uh, know.
有点事我觉得应该告诉你
Rachel and I are...
瑞秋和我之间吧
We're kind of a thing.
有点关系
-Thing? -Thing. Yes, thing.
-关系  -没错 关系
-You have the sex? -No.
-性关系吗  -不是
No, no. Um, technically, the sex is not being had. But that's, uh...
技术上讲 还没发展到性关系 但是...
That's not the point.
这不是重点
The point is that, uh, Rachel and I should be, uh...
重点是我和瑞秋应该...
Well, Rachel and I should be together.
瑞秋我们是会在一起的
And if you get in the, uh...
可是如果你突然出现在...
-In bed? -No.
-床上  -不是
Ha. No, not where I was going.
我没打算这么说
If you get in the way of us becoming a thing...
如果你耽误了我俩之间关系的话
...then, uh, I would be, well, very sad.
那我肯定会很伤心的
So do you, um?
这么说你...
-You do know a little English? -Little.
-你确实会说点英语的吧  -会一点
Do you know the word crap-weasel?
你知道贱人是什么意思吗
No? That's funny, you are a huge crap-weasel.
不知道吗 那你可真是个大贱人
Chandler, we've been here for an hour doing this. Watch, it's easy.
钱德 我们都练习一个小时了 这很简单啊
Ready?
准备好了吗
Okay? Now try it.
好了 你试试
You gotta whip it.
甩一下它
Look, look. The last candle's about to burn out.
快看 最后一根蜡烛要灭了
Ten, nine, eight, seven...
十 九 八...
...minus 46, minus 47, minus 48...
负四十六 负四十七...
Thank you.
谢谢
Kind of spooky without any lights.
没灯还有点小惊悚呢
Okay, guys, I have the definitive one.
看我的必杀技
Uh, Ross...
罗斯
This probably isn't the best time to bring it up...
现在提这事可能不太合适
...but you have to throw a party for Monica.
但是你得给莫妮卡准备一个聚会
-This has been fun. -Yes.
-刚才挺好玩的  -没错
Yes. Thanks for, uh, letting me use your phone...
谢谢你 让我用你的电话
...and for saving my life.
而且还救了我一命
Well, goodbye, Chandler.
再见了 钱德
I had a great blackout.
这次停电我挺开心的
See you.
拜拜
Hi. Um, I'm account number 7143457.
我的卡号是 7143457
And I don't know if you got any of that...
不知道你们是不是录下来了
...but I would really like a copy of the tape.
但是我十分想要一份刚才的录像副本